[Music]
what's the top three things you need to
know about that sales order about any
customer about a purchase my name is
Mike and I'm going to show you how
co-pilot help you answer those questions
as part of your everyday work with
business Central of course co-pilot is
your AI assistant for work that helps
you get to these insights quickly um and
figure out what's really important and
Urgent with your data and it's
seamlessly integrated into business
Central so you can get to these insights
without having to export your data to
other apps without having your
organization go through extensive AI
training of AI models uh and without you
needing to figure out first and foremost
what do you need to prompt what do you
need to ask co-pilot to get to those
insights let me show you how this
works so here we are on the customer
card and of course business Central is a
really rich business application packed
with information and with your
extensions that you install becomes even
more powerful but that volume of
information is sometimes hard for our
users to figure out what's important and
what's urgent amongst all of that so
we've crafted this new space a new stage
for copilot to present a concise and
simple summary in this case about Alpine
Ski
house and we call this the summary fact
box as you can see has provided three
concise bullet points here um they're
tailored to my role which happens to be
that of a a receivable admin and you can
see it's it's uh found really important
information first of all that this
customer has an overdue amount that
needs to be paid um here's our payment
terms and also an average collection
period of 40 days that doesn't quite
match up and also some important
information about the sales and the
posted invoices for this customer so
it's all being summarized here in an
easily digestable format now this is
also interactive so I can click to drill
down into any of this information let's
try to balance here and notice what
happens as I click on the balance it has
um highlighted the field on the page
that is the source of that information
this is a fact that has come from within
the business Central database so all of
these summaries are grounded in facts
from your business
data um let's try a different one 40
days where did that come from I'm
curious about that information let's
drill into that and notice here how it's
actually scrolled down and expanded a
fast tab which is the statistics fast
tab here on the page and in visually
indicated the field that powers that
Insight average collection period being
40 days
here now normally I'd have to scroll all
the way down to this information expand
and dig around just to compile this info
that's really useful before I enter a
conversation with this customer but
copilot has done that summarizing for me
how fantastic is
that now those are two data points which
happen to be on the same page Copilot
also gets information from related Pages
through your fact boxes and also through
the actions and related uh actions and
things like statistics pages that are
related to this uh particular customer
so let's try to posted sales invoices
and I will go straight to my list of
invoices filtered to this customer of
Alpine ski house and they're all here
for me to browse around and look at
their invoicing history before I start
that
conversation so we've created a way for
you to really just dig into your data
explore that data and figure out where
you need to go and act uh to make some
change and of course if you're curious
for more insights you simply click show
more show more brings up the co-pilot
Pane and this is a great space for
co-pilot to present those same data
points those same insights and then some
more on top of that as well there's a
bit more space here to to show that
information and here it is the summary
for the same customer card you can see
it's got similar information there
and this is also interactive so even
from chat from the copilot pane you can
actually interact with all of these
summaries but more importantly this is a
great place where you can ask follow-up
questions like sled setup reminders for
our
customers so by having this information
in the co-pilot pane um you can ask
follow-up questions on that data on
related data as well or how to do things
in business
Central now here as you can see we have
um some information about how to use and
set up reminders in business Central
that's great because now I can use that
next time to make sure that um you know
my customers do pay on time where does
all this information come from it's from
the fields on that record that you're
looking at it's from the information in
the fact boxes and it's from those
related Pages especially statistics
Pages let's close out the copilot Pane
and I want to dig into that delayed
payment so let's check out the invoice
is problematic here and that's the one
here for Alpine Sky house just drill
into that
and even here on the posted sales
invoice we also have a summary from
co-pilot now summaries are essentially
um a way for co-pilot to present
information to me and this is all
information and data that I have access
to so uh co-pilot acts on my behalf it
SCS the database for this this data um
based on my permissions so it doesn't
have access to any more information than
what I would normally be able to see and
simply presents that in a very verbose
format so here I want to act on this
particular invoice You Know spoken to
the customer now and we just want to set
the uh payment method code here to uh
they want to make a bank payment so
we'll type bank and now we'll just okay
that and we've taken action to uh help
understand the current situation with
this customer so the last tip I have for
you here is refreshing that summary so
sometimes you will make some changes to
your data or you know of somebody who's
made a change to that same record and
you just want to get the latest summary
so for that you can use the uh the
button up here to regenerate that
summary and give you the latest and
greatest now um while this summary may
seem quite simple you can certainly see
the opportunity at unlocks for our
future um and while in preview uh we're
focused on this these sources of
information these knowledge sources and
over time we really think we can grow
this into so many interesting and
exciting ways to provide you a better
and better 360 view of uh in this case a
posted invoice but also about customers
vendors products fixed assets you name
it so when you upgrade to version 26 of
business Central you'll find this
feature available no matter which
country localization and your
environment no matter which language you
use so give it a try um it's available
everywhere and it works also with your
custom entities as well and with your
custom fields on those pages U now you
can't directly extend or create your own
summaries yes if you're a developer uh
but there are different ways to actually
influence uh through your code those
summaries that copilot comes up with and
I've dropped a link just below this
video where you can learn more about how
to do that not just for this feature but
also for other co-pilot features as well
so what are you waiting for this is when
you stop watching this video you dive
into business Central and you give this
a try on your favorite records on your
favorite Pages let us know how that goes
we we love uh to hear your feedback and
your experiences with uh co-pilot
summaries and I wish you a productive
day and thanks for watching